<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<game xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tfhenning/tgschema/master/TabletopGamesMetadataSchema1.0.xsd">
    <title type="preferred" lang="eng">Game of Thrones: the board game</title>
    <title type="alternate" lang="eng">George R.R. Martin's A Game of Thrones: the board game</title>
    <contributor type="personal" role="designers" source="LCNAF" sourceID="no2015113144">Petersen, Christian T. (Game designer)</contributor>
    <contributor type="corporate" role="publishers" source="LCNAF" sourceID="no2013024322">Fantasy Flight Publishing</contributor>
    <contributor type="personal" role="developers">Walden, Jason</contributor>
    <contributor type="personal" role="rightsholders" source="LCNAF" sourceID="n80160390">Martin, George R. R.</contributor>
    <edition>Second edition</edition>
    <date type="copyright">2011</date>
    <description>"Claim the Iron Throne and the lands of Westeros! King Robert Baratheon is dead and the kingdoms of Westeros brace for impending war. House Lannister, whose daughter Cersei was Robert's queen, claims the throne for her young son, Joffrey. From his seat on the isle of Dragonstone, Robert's younger brother Stannis rightfully demands the throne for himself. On the Iron Isles, House Greyjoy is about to embark on a second rebellion, but this time with a grander goal. In the north, House Stark gathers its strength to defend what is right. In the south, wealthy House Tyrell harbors an old ambition to sit on the Iron Throne but must be ever wary of the ancient House Martell and its legacy of vengeance. All the while, in the north far beyond the Wall, the wildling threat steadily grows in strength. As armies gather and ravens fly, a clash of kings is inevitable. Based on the best-selling novel series A Song of Ice and Fire by George R.R. Martin, A Game of Thrones: The Board Game allows players to take control of the great Houses of Westeros and embark on an epic struggle to claim the Iron Throne. Immerse yourself in a game of clever planning, careful allocation of power, and delicate diplomacy, all in the exciting flavor of A Song of Ice and Fire. This updated 2nd Edition of the best-selling board game brings a host of enhancements to your A Game of Thrones experience. It incorporates elements from the previous expansions, including ports, garrisons, wilding cards, and siege engines. In addition, it introduces welcome new innovations; convenient player screens hide your careful planning from prying eyes, while the new Tides of Battle cards convey the risks of war"--Back of box.</description>
    <language>eng</language>
    <contents>1 rulebook, 1 game board, 138 plastic units, 42 house cards, 30 Westeros cards, 9 Wildling cards, 24 tides of battle cards, 6 player screens, 90 order tokens, 120 power tokens, 18 influence tokens, 6 supply tokens, 14 neutral forces tokens, 6 victory point tokens, 6 garrison tokens, 1 Iron Throne token, 1 Valyrian Steel token, 1 messenger raven token, 1 game round marker, 1 wildling threat token, 1 king's court overlay, 2 reference sheets</contents>
    <dimensions type="weight">2 kg</dimensions>
    <dimensions type="board">84 x 56 cm.</dimensions>
    <dimensions type="container">30 x 30 x 7 cm.</dimensions>
    <identifier type="ISBN">9781589947207</identifier>
    <identifier type="UPC">9781589947207</identifier>
    <instructions lang="eng">https://images-cdn.fantasyflightgames.com/filer_public/30/4f/304f72e3-4fe4-4f91-bfbe-75133161b092/va65_agot2_rulebook_web.pdf</instructions>
    <playerInformation>
        <minPlayerNumber>3</minPlayerNumber>
        <maxPlayerNumber>6</maxPlayerNumber>
        <minRecommendedAge>14</minRecommendedAge>
    </playerInformation>
    <gameplayInformation>
        <minPlayTime>02:00:00</minPlayTime>
        <maxPlayTime>04:00:00</maxPlayTime>
        <difficulty source="BGG">3.71/5</difficulty>
        <mechanism>Area control</mechanism>
        <mechanism>Auction/bidding</mechanism>
        <mechanism>Hand management</mechanism>
    </gameplayInformation>
    <award>Ludoteca Ideale Official Selection, 2013</award>
    <subject source="LCSH">Warfare</subject>
    <subject source="LCSH">Diplomacy</subject>
    <subject source="LCSH">Monarchy</subject>
    <genre source="Langsdale Game Genre Headings" sourceID="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/ubgame/1092">Strategy board games</genre>
    <genre source="Langsdale Game Genre Headings" sourceID="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/ubgame/1081">Fantasy board games</genre>
    <genre source="Langdale Game Genre Headings" sourceID="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/ubgame/1096">War board games</genre>
    <series>Game of Thrones: the board game</series>
    <price source="Fantasy Flight Games">$59.95</price>
    <gameVariantInformation>
        <gameVariantTitle lang="eng">Variant game with all expansions</gameVariantTitle>
        <gameVariantInstructions>https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2309997/variant-game-all-expansions</gameVariantInstructions>
        <gameVariantNote>This game variant requires all expansion packs.</gameVariantNote>
    </gameVariantInformation>
    <relatedWorkInformation>
        <relatedWorkTitle type="book" source="LCNAF" sourceID="no2018154609">Martin, George R. R. Game of thrones</relatedWorkTitle>
        <relatedWorkNote>This game is based on George R.R. Martin's A Song of Ice and Fire series. A Game of Thrones is the first novel in the series.</relatedWorkNote>
    </relatedWorkInformation>
    <relatedWorkInformation>
        <relatedWorkTitle source="LCNAF" sourceID="no2011110818">Game of thrones (Television program)</relatedWorkTitle>
        <relatedWorkNote>The Game of Thrones television series on HBO is based on George R.R. Martin's A Song of Ice and Fire series. While not directly related to the board game, it may be of interest to players.</relatedWorkNote>
    </relatedWorkInformation>
    <note>This game has several expansions. For more information, see https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgamefamily/4683/game-thrones-board-game.</note>
</game>